{
  "games":
    [{
        "name": "space_odyssey",
        "rooms": [
          {
          "name": "kitchen",
            "description": "You're in the most beautiful kitchen you have ever seen.",
          "usefulItem": [
            {
              "name": "match",
              "dialogs": [
                "On the floor there is a single [match].","You use the match to light the stove!", "Seems like the pilot light is out."
              ]
            }],
          "actor": {
            "name": "duckling",
            "dialogs": [
              "In the middle of the room, is a [Duckling] playing with a yellow rubber duck in a big fish tank",
              "I heard [Fish] wants his bowl back! Make sure to tell them I said thank you for letting me borrow it!",
              "Thank you",
              "Quack Quack"
            ],
            "item": {"name": ""},
            "trivia": [
              {
                "question": " An adult male duck is referred to as a _____?",
                "answers": ["Mandrake", "Drake", "Quacker", "Duckle"],
                "correctAnswer": "Drake"
              },
              {
                "question": "Many birds have a gland that produces a waxy oil to waterproof feathers called a _____ gland?",
                "answers": ["Mandrake", "Drake", "Uropygial", "Duckle"],
                "correctAnswer": "Uropygial"
              },
              {
                "question": "How long after hatching are Ducklings able to walk and leave the nest?",
                "answers": ["immediately", "a couple hours", "a day", "a couple days"],
                "correctAnswer": "a couple hours"
              },
              {
                "question": "a group of ducks can be called a ______?",
                "answers": ["druid", "deckle", "cast", "raft"],
                "correctAnswer": "raft"
              },
              {
                "question": "How many eyelids does a duck have?",
                "answers": ["0", "1", "2", "3"],
                "correctAnswer": "3"
              }
            ]
          }
          ,
          "adjacent_rooms": ["stock room", "dorms"]
        },
          {
            "name": "stock room",
            "description": "You're in a small cramped [STOCK ROOM]",
            "usefulItem": [
              {
                "name": "none"
              }],
            "actor": {
              "name": "duck",
              "dialogs": [
                "A french [Duck] is preparing a meal. They look very busy",
                "Don't Bother Me! I am busy preparing a meal. If you can, fix the stove that would help me out.",
                "Thank you for fixing the stove! I'm bad with numbers and can only remember the last number was 2, Sorry. Here's a reward for your trouble.",
                "Quack Quack"
              ],
              "item": {"name": ""},
              "trivia": [
                {
                  "question": " An adult male duck is referred to as a _____?",
                  "answers": ["Mandrake", "Drake", "Quacker", "Duckle"],
                  "correctAnswer": "Drake"
                },
                {
                  "question": "Many birds have a gland that produces a waxy oil to waterproof feathers called a _____ gland?",
                  "answers": ["Mandrake", "Drake", "Uropygial", "Duckle"],
                  "correctAnswer": "Uropygial"
                },
                {
                  "question": "How long after hatching are Ducklings able to walk and leave the nest?",
                  "answers": ["immediately", "a couple hours", "a day", "a couple days"],
                  "correctAnswer": "a couple hours"
                },
                {
                  "question": "a group of ducks can be called a ______?",
                  "answers": ["druid", "deckle", "cast", "raft"],
                  "correctAnswer": "raft"
                },
                {
                  "question": "How many eyelids does a duck have?",
                  "answers": ["0", "1", "2", "3"],
                  "correctAnswer": "3"
                }
              ]
            },
            "adjacent_rooms": ["kitchen"]
          },
          {
            "name": "cock pit",
            "description": "You're in the [COCK PIT]",
            "usefulItem": [
              {
                "name": "none"
              }],
            "actor": {
              "name": "dog",
              "dialogs": [
                "A [Dog] is sitting in the captains chair. They look very busy",
                "Help my crew and I might think about not kicking you off the ship stranger",
                "Thank you for helping my crew. The code to the [keypad] is 4982!",
              "Woof!"
              ],
              "item": {"name": ""},
              "trivia": [
                {
                  "question": "An upright and still tail indicates that a dog is _______?",
                  "answers": ["scared or curious", "focused and excited", "angry", "anxious"],
                  "correctAnswer": "focused and excited"
                },
                {
                  "question": "Greyhounds can run up to ___ miles per hour.?",
                  "answers": ["23", "38", "44", "53"],
                  "correctAnswer": "44"
                },
                {
                  "question": "The first dog superstar was ________?",
                  "answers": ["Air Bud", "Rin Tin Tin", "Taco Bell Chihuahua", "Lassie"],
                  "correctAnswer": "Rin Tin Tin"
                },
                {
                  "question": "A Russian dog named ______ was the first animal in space and traveled around the Earth in 1957?",
                  "answers": ["Lukraim", "Laika", "Wallachia", "Larissa"],
                  "correctAnswer": "Laika"
                },
                {
                  "question": "Dalmatian puppies are born with ____?",
                  "answers": ["all their spots", "0 spots", "most of their spots", "some of their spots"],
                  "correctAnswer": "0 spots"
                }
              ]
            },
            "adjacent_rooms": ["engine room", "dorms"]
          },
          {
            "name": "engine room",
            "description": " You're in a small cramped [ENGINE ROOM]",
            "usefulItem": [
              {
                "name": "none",
                "dialogs": [
                  ]
              }],
            "actor": {
              "name": "horse",
              "dialogs": ["A large [Horse] is pacing back and forth",
                "I need to find my wrench, the captain told me you came to help. Can you help me find my wrench",
                "Thank you for finding my wrench, now i can fix the escape pod engine. The first number to the code is 4",
                "Ney!"],
              "item": {"name": ""},
              "trivia": [
                {
                  "question": "Horses are measured in ____?",
                  "answers": ["centimeter", "hands", "meters", "feet"],
                  "correctAnswer": "hands"
                },
                {
                  "question": "Horses came from what continent?",
                  "answers": ["Asia", "Europe", "Africa", "North America"],
                  "correctAnswer": "Europe"
                },
                {
                  "question": " A baby horse is called a _____?",
                  "answers": ["Ferol", "Foal", "Voal", "Colt"],
                  "correctAnswer": "Foal"
                },
                {
                  "question": "The original horse was no larger than a ____?",
                  "answers": ["rhino", "golden retriever", "large deer", "reindeer"],
                  "correctAnswer": "golden retriever"
                },
                {
                  "question": "Horses ______ burp?",
                  "answers": ["can", "can't", "can", "can"],
                  "correctAnswer": "can't"
                }
              ]
            },
            "adjacent_rooms": ["escape hatch", "cock pit"]
          },
          {
            "name": "dorms",
            "description": " You're in a small cramped [DORMS]",
            "usefulItem": [
              {
                "name": "match",
                "dialogs": ["On the floor there is a single [match].", "You use the match to light the stove!", "Seems like the pilot light is out."]
              }],
            "actor": {
              "name": "none",
              "dialogs": [],
              "item": {"name": ""},
              "trivia": []
            },
            "adjacent_rooms": ["cock pit", "kitchen"]
          },
          {
            "name": "escape hatch",
            "description": "You're in a small cramped [ESCAPE HATCH]",
            "usefulItem": [{"name": "none", "dialogs":[]}],
            "actor": {
              "name": "fish",
              "dialogs": ["A [Fish] is repairing some air lock doors. They look very busy", "That [Cat] keeps trying to swipe at me! I need my [fishbowl] to protect me. Can you go talk to the [Duckling] who is using my [fishbowl] as a swimming pool?",
              "No way! I got my fishbowl back. Thank you so much stranger! The third number to the [POD] [keypad] is 8!", "Glub glub"],
              "item": {"name": ""},
              "trivia": [
                {
                  "question": " What is the loudest fish?",
                  "answers": ["clapper", "croaker", "gulper", "glubber"],
                  "correctAnswer": "croaker"
                },
                {
                  "question": "A Lungfish can live out of water for _______?",
                  "answers": ["couple months", "several years", "couple weeks", "several hours"],
                  "correctAnswer": "several years"
                },
                {
                  "question": "Oldest known fish was ___ years old Lungfish?",
                  "answers": ["45", "65", "95", "35"],
                  "correctAnswer": "65"
                },
                {
                  "question": "Only fish that has eye lids is the __________ ?",
                  "answers": ["whale", "shark", "lungfish", "eel"],
                  "correctAnswer": "shark"
                },
                {
                  "question": "The slowest fish is a ________?",
                  "answers": ["slothfish", "jellyfish", "starfish", "seahorse"],
                  "correctAnswer": "seahorse"
                }
              ]
            },
            "adjacent_rooms": ["engine room", "pod"]
          },
          {
            "name": "pod",
            "description": "You're in a small cramped [POD]",
            "usefulItem": [
              {
                "name": "wrench",
                "dialogs": ["A [wrench] sits on the table. Should you take it?", "You use the WRENCH to dig through the tunnel", "If only you had some type of digging tool"]
              },
              {
                "name": "keypad",
                "dialogs": ["A [keypad] is attached to the display of the pod to activate it.", "something", "A [keypad] is attached to the display of the pod to activate it."]
              }],
            "actor": {
              "name": "cat",
              "dialogs": ["A [Cat] is lounging on a high perch.", "I love messing with [Fish], but I want more exciting toys! Can you Steal the laser pointer from Dog. He keeps it in the [DORMS]",
              "Thank you for the toy! I heard you wanted to use the [POD], I remember the second number was the number of lives a [Cat] has.", "Meow"],
              "item": {"name": ""},
              "trivia": [
                {
                  "question": "Cats move with their right feet and then their left feet. The only other animals that walk this way are ________?",
                  "answers": ["horses and rhinos", "camels and giraffes", "elephants and zebras", "wolves and iguanas"],
                  "correctAnswer": "camels and giraffes"
                },
                {
                  "question": "Cats have whiskers on the back of their ______, as well?",
                  "answers": ["ears", "front legs", "back legs", "tail"],
                  "correctAnswer": "front legs"
                },
                {
                  "question": "A cat with a question-mark-shaped tail is asking, “________”?",
                  "answers": ["Who are you", "Want to Play", "Want to Fight", "Want to get something to eat"],
                  "correctAnswer": "Want to Play"
                },
                {
                  "question": "Meowing is a behavior that cats developed exclusively to ___________?",
                  "answers": ["communicate with kittens", "communicate with people", "trick prey", "find a mate"],
                  "correctAnswer": "communicate with people"
                },
                {
                  "question": "A ______ cat was born in Denmark in 1995. Some people believe that high levels of copper in the water pipes nearby may have given his fur a verdigris effect?",
                  "answers": ["blue", "green", "red", "purple"],
                  "correctAnswer": "green"
                }
              ]
            },
            "adjacent_rooms": ["escape hatch"]
          }
        ]
    },{
      "name": "jonin_exam",
      "fighters" : [
        {
          "name" : "Kakashi",
          "ninjaHP": 10,
          "intro": "\nLooks like Kakashi is preparing to use his Chidori attack",
          "question": "\nHow would you like to attack? \n 1: Use a Genjutsu attack \n 2: Ninjutsu attack \n 3: Dodge",
          "attacks" : [
            {
              "name": "Genjutsu Attack",
              "text": "\nYou used your genjutsu and was able to defeat the opponent!! \nWow that was fast!! ....and the winner is YOU!!"
            },
            {
              "name": "Ninjutsu Attack",
              "text": "\nKakashi: He thinks he got me with that move lol...\nYour opponent has defeated you before you could blink!!!\nBetter luck next time!!!"
            },
            {
              "name": "Dodge",
              "text": "\n Kakashi: Haaa I'll see about that!\nYou dodged the attack but it was a distraction and your opponent defeated you with a blazing kick to the back of your head!\nCall the medics this match is over!!"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "name" : "Gaara",
          "ninjaHP": 10,
          "intro": "\nGaara throws a sand bullet fast!!",
          "question": "\nHow would you like to attack? \n 1: Use a Genjutsu attack \n 2: Ninjutsu attack \n 3: Dodge",
          "attacks" : [
            {
              "name": "Genjutsu Attack",
              "text": "\nYou attempted to prepare a genjutsu attack but Gaara's sand bullet got to you too fast\nWow it tore through your chest!\nThe winner is Gaara!!!"
            },
            {
              "name": "Ninjutsu Attack",
              "text": "\nYou attacked Gaara with your flying leg attack while dodging his sand bullet!\nGaara is out cold from that attack, you have won the match!!"
            },
            {
              "name": "Dodge",
              "text": "\nGaara: Whaaaaat!!!! How are you moving so fast!!!!!!\nGreat you dodged it!, then you used your speedy Ninjutsu attacks to defeat Garaa!!\nYou Won Congrats!!!"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "name" : "Killer B",
          "ninjaHP": 10,
          "intro": "\nKiller B starts rapping after the battle starts",
          "question": "\nHow would you like to attack? \n 1: Use a Genjutsu attack \n 2: Ninjutsu attack \n 3: Join in and rap also",
          "attacks" : [
            {
              "name": "Genjutsu Attack",
              "text": "\nYou used your genjutsu and was able to defeat the opponent!!\\nKiller B Genjutsu is too advanced! He broke out of your visual prowess and used his lightning sword attack to defeat you! all while he was rapping!\nYou lose!!"
            },
            {
              "name": "Ninjutsu Attack",
              "text": "\nKiller B: Yo you trynna disrespect me while I'm spittin my raps!! Take This!!!!\nhe uses his 8 tails ability to defeat you quickly!!!\nYou have a lost this match, try again next year!!"
            },
            {
              "name": "Dodge",
              "text": "\nYou joined Killer B and spit some of your own bars!\nKiller B: Yoooo I like this kid those raps were all that!!!\n\nKiller B: yo I can't compete with that I gotta go think of some more raps!\nB forfeits the match and you are the winner!!!"
            }
          ]
        }
      ],
      "villages": [
        {
          "name": "The Hidden Leaf Village",
          "intro": "\nLooks like you will be facing the Legendary Kakashi"
        },
        {
          "name": "The Village Hidden in the Stones",
          "intro": "\nOk, you'll be fighting Gaara"
        },
        {
          "name": "The Village Hidden in the Clouds",
          "intro": "\nYou will be matched against Killer B"
        }
      ]
    }]

}
